Sylvester Rosa Koehler
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Sylvester Rosa Koehler papers
1833-1904 (bulk 1870-1890)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
S. R. (Sylvester Rosa) Koehler
5.3 linear feet
The Sylvester Rosa Koehler papers measure 5.3 linear feet and date from 1833 to 1904, with the bulk of the material dating from 1870 to 1890. The collection consists primarily of Koehler's extensive correspondence to and from many notable artists and printmakers such as Jean F. Harfin, John M. Falconer, Frederick Juengling, and James D. Smillie, as well as friends, and family members and professional correspondence concerning Koehler's activities as a writer, curator, and editor of the American Art Review. The collection also contains financial records and other miscellaneous items.
Biographical Note
Art historian and curator Sylvester Rosa Koehler was born in Leipsic, Germany in 1837. He came to the United States with his family in 1849 and settled in Roxbury, Massachusetts. In 1868 he became the Technical Manager of Louis Prang and Company, a lithograph publisher. Koehler was the founding editor of the American Art Review, which commissioned artists for original etchings, and ran from 1879-1881. Through this publication, as well as his work as writer and exhibition curator, Koehler encouraged an American etching revival in the 1880s. Koehler also published many books on American art and was the first Curator of Prints at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. From 1886 to 1900 he served as the first Curator of Graphic Arts at the United States National Museum, part of the Smithsonian Institution. While there, he created a permanent and traveling exhibition of graphic arts. His knowlege of the art world and his extensive personal contacts brought many important collections to the museum. Koehler died in Littleton, New Hampshire in 1900.
Scope and Content Note
The Sylvester Rosa Koehler papers measure 5.3 linear feet and date from 1833 to 1904, with the bulk of the material dating from 1870 to 1890. The collection consists primarily of Koehler's extensive correspondence to and from many notable artists and printmakers such as Jean F. Harfin, John M. Falconer, Frederick Juengling, and James D. Smillie, as well as friends, and family members and professional correspondence concerning Koehler's activities as a writer, curator, and editor of the American Art Review. The collection also contains financial records and other miscellaneous items.
Correspondence includes hundreds of letters to and from Koehler. Correspondents include many prominent artists, engravers, architects, art critics, curators, historians, journalists, authors, educators, publishers, and others during the late 1800s. Also found is correspondence with family, most of which is in German. Much of the correspondence concerns Koehler's role as editor of the publication American Art Review, and his work promoting American graphic arts.
Financial Records include Koehler's receipts, primarily from 1885, and a handwritten estimate of costs for publishing the American Art Review.
Miscellany includes biographical information on the wood engraver, Alexander Anderson, various notes by unidentified authors, news clippings, programs and handwritten song texts for music performances.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 3 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1833-1904, undated (Box 1-5; 5.0 linear feet)
Series 2: Financial Records, 1870-1890, undated (Box 6; 14 folders)
Series 3: Miscellany, 1859-1896, undated (Box 6; 10 folders)
Related Material
Additional correspondence can be found at the Library of Congress, which houses the Papers of S. R. Koehler, 1868-1904, and includes approximately 3,500 letters. Syracuse University Library houses S. R. Koehler Correspondence, 1879-1896, and includes 107 items.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents and under "Names" when they are creators or contributors.
Subjects:
Anderson, Alexander, 1775-1870; American Art Review
Subjects-Topical:
Art literature; Artists -- United States; Prints -- 19th century; Art historians -- Massachusetts -- Boston; Museum curators -- Massachusetts -- Boston
Names:
Juengling, Frederick, 1846-1889; Smillie, James David, 1833-1909; Falconer, John Mackie, 1820-1903; Harfin, Jean F.
Provenance
The collection was purchased from Argosy Book Stores, Inc, in 1959. A letter from John Sartain and eleven letters from William Merritt Chase were donated by Charles E. Feinberg, 1955-1962. The Archives microfilmed the entire collection on reels D182-191, 3533-3534, and D30.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. research facility.
Alternative Forms Available
The microfilm is available on microfilm reels D182-191, 3533-3534, and D30. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of material described in this finding aid does not reflect the order of the material on microfilm.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1833-1904, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1-5; 5.0 linear feet)
  Koehler's correspondence is extensive and contains letters to and from over 300 different correspondents. For his career as curator and art critic, Koehler maintained correspondence with many American painters, including Jean F. Harfin, Edwin Howland Blashfield, Emil Carlsen, William Merritt Chase, John Robinson Tait, Samuel Colman, Thomas Wilmer Dewing, Anna Lea Merritt, and Walter Shirlaw. Also found in this series is correspondence with American engravers and illustrators, many featured in American Art Review, including John Sartain, Stephen James Ferris, William Baxter Closson, Henry Farrer, R. Swain Gifford, John M. Falconer, Frederick Juengling, Robert Hoskin, Gustav Kruell, Stephen A. Schoff, J. C. Nicoll, James D. Smillie, William Wellstood, Charles A. Platt, Peter Moran, and Stephen Parrish. Koehler also corresponded with many architects, engineers, and designers, including George Corliss, William Rotch Ware, P. B. Wight, Henry Van Brunt, Russell Sturgis, Julius Schweinfurth, and Arthur Rotch.
  Koehler corresponded with art critics such as Mariana Van Rensselaer, Samuel G. W. Benjamin, Russell Sturgis, Clarence Cook, and Charles C. Perkins, historians such as Charles Henry Hart, and journalists including Ottilie Assing and George Julian Harney. Also found in this collection is correspondence with authors such as Ednah D. Cheney, educators including Kuno Francke and William Unger, and museum directors and curators such as A. Duncan Savage, W. M. R. French and William MacLeod. As a writer and editor, Koehler corresponded with several publishers, including Cassell and Company, Estes and Lauriat, and E. A. Seeman.
  Also of note, is Koehler's correspondence with many prominent people working in other fields including scientists Henry C. Angell and Wilhelm von Bezold, archaeologists Luigi di Cesnola, Frederic Putnam, and Otis T. Mason, natural scientists Thomas Meehan and Edward Sylvester Morse, music scholar Waldo S. Pratt, and astronomer Edward C. Pickering.
  Users should note that a significant portion of the correspondence is in German. A few letters within the collection are neither to or from Koehler, but concern American art. It is unclear if Koehler collected these letters.
  - Adams, Charlotte, 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allen, Frederick H., 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amoore, H. E., 1879-1881, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Andrew, George T., 1880-1886 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Andrews, Robert D., 1879 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Angell, Henry C., 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Assing, Ottilie, 1867-1884, undated, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 8-13)
  - Attwood, Gilbert, 1875-1879 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A, Miscellaneous: A-Al, 1873-1887 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Adams Express Company
    Adler, Felix
    Adsit, Mrs. C. D.
    Allen, J. A.
    Allen, O. H.
    Allen, Walter
  - A, Miscellaneous: Am, 1875-1889 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Amand-Durand
    American Architect and Building News
    American Art Association
    American Bank Note Company
    American Numismatic and Archeological Society
    American Photo-Engraving Company
    American Polytechnic Company
    American Tract Society
  - A, Miscellaneous: An-Ap, 1879-1889 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Anderson, A. A.
    Anderson, Dr. William
    John Andrew & Son Co.
    Andrews, Ellen
    Andrews, Frances
    Anthony, A. V. S.
    E. & H. T. Anthony & Co.
    Appleton, T. G.
    D. Appleton & Co.
  - A, Miscellaneous: Ar-Av, 1875-1889 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Ardrey, James G.
    Armstrong & Company
    Art Interchange
    Astor, Mrs. [William]
    Atkinson, Edward
    Avery, Sam. P.
  - Bacher, Otto H., 1880-1884 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Baker, W. S., 1873-1882 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bartle, George P., 1885-1886 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bartlett, Francis, 1881, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bartlett, Truman Howe, 1880-1887, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - Beckwith, J. Carroll, 1881, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bellows, A. F., 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Benjamin, Samuel G. W., 1879-1881, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-30)
  - Bezold, Welhelm von, 1875-1877, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
  - Bishop, W. H., 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Blake, W. P., 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1880-1885 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Brennan, A., 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bridgman, F. A., 1880-1886 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Brown, George L., 1879-1885 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Brown, H. Louisa, 1887-1889 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bunner, Andrew F., 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - B, Miscellaneous: Ba, 1836, 1870-1895 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Baba, Tatui
    Bacon, Edwin M.
    Baer, William J.
    Bagley, George B.
    Balch, F. A.
    Baldwin, Caleb
    Ballue, A.
    B[annan?], S. Z.
    Bannister, E. M.
    Barnard, Edward M.
    Barry, August
    Barton, E. M.
    Bastian, Huber
    Bates, Geo. A.
    Bates, Miss S. A.
    Bauch, A.
    Baudry, Miss R. M.
    Baxter, Sylvester
    Bayer, Mrs. H. H.
    Baylies, W. S.
    Beavan, John
  - B, Miscellaneous: Be, 1870-1895 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Becket, Maria J. C.
    Beesley, J.
    Bell, William
    Belmont, August
    Benjamin, William Evarts
    Bergandorff, Carl
    Berger & Wirth
    Bergerat, E.
    Berlin, Dr. F.
    Bernheim Baur & Co.
    Bette, Paul
  - B, Miscellaneous: Bi-Bl, 1879-1886 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Bigelow, M. T.
    Blackshear, T. B.
    Blair & Son
    Bliss, Chas. M.
    Bloor, A. J.
    Blum, J.
    Blum, Robert
    Blume, Andreas
  - B, Miscellaneous: Bo, 1871-1890 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Bobbett, Walter
    Bollé, Carl
    Bonn, J. H.
    Bonpiani, Sofia
    Booth, George
    Boston Art Club
    Boston Public Library
    Borrman, S. L.
    Boyd, Mrs. H. H.
  - B, Miscellaneous: Br-Bu, 1842, 1870-1889 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Bradford, William
    Brandis Manufacturing Co.
    Breton, Sidney G.
    Brigham, William F.
    Brinch, William Brinkley, Captain F.
    Brinton, D. G.
    Brock, F. B.
    Brooks, Noah
    Brown, J. Appleton
    Brown, J. G.
    Brown, Marie A.
    Brownell, William C.
    Bruce, W. J.
    B[rueck?], H. V.
    B[ruer?], Edward B.
    Bruere, Theodore
    B[uehn?], Ferdinand
    Bulloch, A. G.
    Bunce, A. B.
    Burns, M. J.
    Burrage, William Clarence
  - Cadart, Veuve A., 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Carlsen, Emil, 1881-1887 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cassell and Company, 1882-1889, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 48-53)
  - Cesnola, Luigi P. di, 1878-1880 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Champney, J. Wells, 1877-1885 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Chase, Harry, 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Chase, William Merritt, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Cheney, Ednah D., 1879-1890, 1904, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 58-59)
  - Clark, Jr., William J., 1879-1888 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Clarke, J. Edwards, 1874-1886 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Clarke, Joseph Thatcher, 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Clarke, Thomas B., 1881-1886, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Clement, Clara Erskine, 1878-1880, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 64-65)
  - Closson, William Baxter, 1880-1890, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 66-69)
  - Cole, J. Foxcroft, 1879-1889 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Colman, Samuel, 1879-1888 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Cook, Clarence, 1871-1887, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 72-75)
  - Corliss, George, 1879-1890, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 76-80)
  - Cross, Charles R., 1877-1878, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Crum and Ringler, 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - C, Miscellaneous: Ca, 1879-1889 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    Cabot, Edw. C. (Cabot & Chandler)
    Cabot, J. E. (Cabot & Chandler)
    Call, Dr. Norman
    Carmalt, W. H.
    Carpenter, H. Bernard
    Carter, Charles M.
    Castellani, Alessandro
  - C, Miscellaneous: Ce-Ch, 1870-1890 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    Centennial Congress of Liberals
    Century Co.
    Century Magazine
    Chadwick, Charles W.
    Champier, Victor
    Champney, Edwin G.
    Chandler, Frank W.
    Channing, Eva
    Chapman, J. Linton
    Chase, J. Eastman
    Chérié, A.
    Chicago World
    Chick, Edward E.
    Christele, Charles
    Church, F. S.
  - C, Miscellaneous: Cl-Col, 1871-1895 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    Claghorn, J. Raymond
    Clark, Charles E.
    Clark, David H.
    Clark, T. M.
    Clement, E. H.
    Clements, Gabrielle D.
    Cleveland, H. W. S.
    Coale, Samuel A., Jr.
    Codman, C. H. and Abby
    Cole, Timothy
    Collor, W. C.
    Coltman, Ora A.
    Colvin, Sidney
  - C, Miscellaneous: Con-Cr, 1874-1889 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    Conely, William B.
    Coolidge, Cassius M.
    Corwin, Charles A.
    Cox, Kenyon
    Coyriere, E. Miriam
    Cram, George W.
    Cronemeyer, G.
    Crosman, J. C.
    Cross, K. A.
    Crotzer, H. W.
    Crowninshield, F.
  - C, Miscellaneous: Cu, 1879-1887 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    Cund, Thomas
    Cundall, H. M.
    Cundall, Joseph
    Currier, E. W.
    Curtis, Albert W.
    Curtis, Charles B.
  - Davidson, Thomas, 1879-1881, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 88-89)
  - Davis, John P., 1880-1885 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - de Katow, A., 1879-1881 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - De Kay, Charles, 1885-1886 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Dewing, Thomas Wilmer, 1880-1886 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Dorety, Joseph H., 1881-1883 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Drake, William H., 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Dunbar, W. H. (Dunbar and Co.), 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Dunham, O. M., 1882-1884 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Durand, John, 1879-1896, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 98-99)
  - D, Miscellaneous: Da-Den, 1878-1897 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    Dalziel, Charles
    Dana, William Jay
    Dana, William P. W.
    Danderhof, Charles A.
    Daniels, J. H.
    Dawson, Henry B.
    Degeon, René
    Dengler, Franz Haver
    Dermett, William S.
  - D, Miscellaneous: Des-Dex, 1879-1889 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    Despard, Matilda
    Despard, W. D.
    Deutsch Verlags-Anstalt
    Deutscher Frauenstimmerechts-Derein
    Devens, Charles
    Devoe, Frederick W. & Co.
    Dewson, Edward
    Dewson, Francis A.
    Dexter, Arthur
  - D, Miscellaneous: Di, 1879-1889 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    Didier, Eugene L.
    Die Kunst Fur Alle
    Diehl, Conrad
    Dillaye, Blanche
    Dimitry, John
    Dingelstedt & Co.
  - D, Miscellaneous: Do-Dy, 1877-1900 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    Doane, W. C.
    Dodd, Mead & Company
    Dodge, C.
    Dodson, Sarah P. B.
    Donlevy, Alice
    Douglas, Lewis H.
    Drake, A. W.
    Dreer, Ferd. J. Dreer
    Du Fais, J. L.
    Dunbar, Charles F.
    Duncan, Florence I.
    Duncan, W. H.
    Duplessis, George
    Dyall, Charles
  - Edelheim, Carl, 1878-1889 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Emmet, Rosina, 1880-1881 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Estes, Dana (Estes and Lauriat), 1877-1884, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - E, Miscellaneous: Ea-Ed, 1879-1889 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Earle, L. C.
    Earll, R. Edward
    Eckman, W. H.
    Eddy, William A.
    Edwards, Ernest
    Edwards-Ficken, H.
  - E, Miscellaneous: Ei-Em, 1866-1896 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Einlasskarte zur Humboldt-Feier
    Elias, Moses
    Eliot, Charles W.
    Eliot, Dr. S.
    Elliot, Lucius A.
    Ely, Lydia
    Emerton, Sibyl C.
  - E, Miscellaneous: En-Ev, 1870-1887 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Englehorn, J.
    Engelmann, Dr. Wilhelm
    Enneking, John J.
    Eppler, John George
    Ernst, C. W.
    Erxleben, August
    Esposizione Nazionale in Milano
    Evans, George W.
  - Falconer, John M., 1879-1893, (8 folders) (Box 2, Folder 9-16)
  - Farrer, Henry, 1878-1889, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-20)
  - Ferris, Stephen James, 1879-1882, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
  - Fillebrown, F. E., 1885-1887 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Filmer, John, 1880-1881 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Francke, Kuno, 1888-1889 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Fraser, W. Lewis, 1883-1890 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Frauenstein, G., 1879-1889 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - French, W. M. R., 1879-1889 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - F, Miscellaneous: Fa, 1879-1886 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Falb, Joseph
    Falke, J.
    Farmer, Ella A.
    Farny, H. F.
    Fausel, D.
  - F, Miscellaneous: Fe-Fi, 1879-1891 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Fehr, Lina
    Fell, Anne Palmer (Mrs. E. Nelson)
    Fellows, F. Wayland
    Fenn, Harry
    Field, Kate
    Finsch, Dr. Otto
    First Japanese Manufacturing and Trading Company
    Fish, William R.
    Fisher, A. J.
    Fiske, Charles H.
  - F, Miscellaneous: Fl-Fo, 18331870-1887 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Fletcher, A. C.
    Folwell, Dr. William W.
    Foote, E. K.
    Foote, Catherine
    Forbes, Edwin
    Forbes Co.
    Ford, H. C.
    Ford, Nellie M.
    Forrer, R.
    Foster, Dwight
    Fowler, Frank
  - F, Miscellaneous: Fr-Fu, 1874-1886 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    French, Daniel C.
    French, Harry W.
    Fuchs & Lang
    Fuchsel, Herman
    Fuller, George
    Fuller, Spencer
  - Gaugengigl, Ignaz M., 1881-1886 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Gesellschaft fur vervielfaltigende Kunst, 1878-1889, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
  - Gifford, R. Swain, 1879-1887, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 37-39)
  - Greenleaf, Edward H., 1878-1889, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
  - Guy, S. J., 1886 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - G, Miscellaneous: Ga-Gi, 1870-1889 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Garrett, Edmund H.
    Garrison, F. J.
    Gazette Des Beaux-Arts
    Geare, R. I.
    Georges, F.
    Gerber, Carl
    Gest, J. H.
    Giani, Carl
    Gibson, Henry C.
    Gilder, Joseph B.
    Gilder, R. W.
  - G, Miscellaneous: Go, 1879-1887, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Goddard, D. A.
    Goepel, Christian
    Gonse, Louis
    Goode, George Brown
    Goodnough, Walter S.
    Gookin, Fred W.
    Gookins, James F.
    Goupil & Co.
  - G, Miscellaneous: Gra, 1877-1895 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Graffield, W.
    Graham, William
    The Graphic
    Graul, Richard
    Gravesande, Ch. Storm van's
    Gravuretype Co.
  - G, Miscellaneous: Gre-Gu, 1864-1888 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Greene, E. B.
    Greenough, W. C.
    Griffin, R. H.
    Griffis, William Elliot
    Griggs, L. D.
    Grundmann, Otto
    Gullick, Thomas J.
    Gummere, Barker
    Gutekunst, F.
  - Hannah, George, 1886-1887 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Harfin, Jean F., 1884-1890, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 48-53)
  - Harney, George Julian, 1870-1889, undated, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 54-60)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1878-1881 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hart, Charles Henry, 1873-1890, (11 folders) (Box 2, Folder 62-72)
  - Heinemann, E., 1886-1887 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Hill, J. Henry, 1880-1889, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 74-75)
  - Hodges, William R., 1879-1886, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 76-78)
  - Hoskin, Robert, 1880-1890, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 79-83)
  - Hunt, T. F., 1880-1886 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - H, Miscellaneous: Ha-Hay, 1870-1889 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    Haeger, A. D.
    Hahn, David F.
    Hahn, George R.
    Hale, Ellen Day
    Hallowell, Sara T.
    Halm, George R.
    Halsey, F. R.
    Hamor, J.
    Hanshatten, Aug.
    Hapgood, M. P.
    Harris, G. W.
    Harrison, Birge
    Hartley, Joseph
    Hartmann, C. Sadakichi
    Hawley, E. H.
    Haynes, H. W.
  - H, Miscellaneous: He, 1880-1890 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    Healy, A. Augustus
    Heinzen, K. F.
    Heliotype Printing Co.
    Helmboldt, H. F.
    Helmboldt, Mathilde
    Henry, Louise
    Hess, Georg
    Hess, Selmar
    Hetherington, Fred A.
    Hewes, H. G.
    Hewitt, Lydia Ely
  - H, Miscellaneous: Hi-Ho, 1870-1891 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    Hiersemann, Karl W.
    Hingst, A.
    Hirshfield, H.
    Hitchcock, J. R. W.
    Hoe, Robert, Jr.
    R. Hoe & Co.
    Hoffman, R.
    Hollingsworth, A. L.
    Hooper, Lucy H.
    Hoppin, Courtland
    Horgan, S. H.
    Houghton, Osgood & Co.
    Houston, Frances C.
    Howland, Henry S.
    Hovenden, Thomas
    Howison, G. H.
  - H, Miscellaneous: Hu, 1870-1889 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    Hubbard, David G.
    Hubbard, Gardiner G.
    Huff, W. A.
    Huish, Marcus
    Hullen, John
    Humpheys, Mary Gay
    Hunt, David
    Hunt, Jane
    Hussey, M. B.
    Hutton, Laurence
    Hyde, William H.
  - Ives, Halsey C., 1879-1888 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - I, Miscellaneous, 1879-1885 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    Illustrated London News
    Ingersoll, H. C.
    Ingersoll, William H.
    Inness, George
    Ipsen, L. S.
    Irwin, Theodore
  - Janes, Margaret P., 1881, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Thomas, 1880-1884, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Juengling, Frederick, 1879-1887, (12 folders) (Box 3, Folder 4-15)
  - J, Miscellaneous: Ja-Je, 1870-1887 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Jackson, John
    Jackson, L. A.
    Jaeger, F.
    Jaeger, Gustel
    Jaeger, William
    Jaeschke, Gustav
    Jameson & Morse
    Janetzky & Company
    Jarves, J. Jackson
    Jeffries, B. Joy
    Jewitt, Llewellyn
  - J, Miscellaneous: Jo-Ju, 1876-1892 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Johns, Frederick
    Charles Eneu Johnson and Company
    Johnson, John G.
    Johnston, John Taylor
    Jones, H. Bolton
    Jones, McDuffre & Stratton
    Juglaris, Thomas
    Junken, E.
    F. W. Jurge & Co.
    Justi, Carl
  - Kelly, George F., 1881-1887 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Kende, S., 1889 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Keppel, Frederick, 1882-1889 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Kimberly, D., 1880-1881 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Kimmel and Voigt, 1879-1886, (7 folders) (Box 3, Folder 22-28)
  - Koehler, Amalie, 1878-1890, undated, (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 29-34)
  - Koehler, Hans J., 1876-1890, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 35-37)
  - Koehler, Hedwig J., 1877-1890, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 38-41)
  - Koehler, Robert, 1878-1879, 1887-1890, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 42-44)
  - Koehler, Walter J., 1870-1890, (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 45-50)
  - Kruell, Gustav, 1879-1885, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 51-55)
  - K, Miscellaneous: Ka, 1870-1889 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    Kaeppel, Gottlob
    Kaiser, Ferd. P.
    Kann, Em.
    Kappes, A.
    Karst, John
  - K, Miscellaneous: Ke-Kim, 1879-1886 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    Keller, George
    Kellogg, William
    Kelly & Co.
    Kennard, M. P.
    Kennedy, W. S.
    Kenyon, W. W.
    Keuffel & Esser
    Kilburn, S. S.
    Kimball, C. F.
    Kimball, David K.
  - K, Miscellaneous: Kin-Kr, 1870-1889 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    King, F. S.
    King, Jas. S.
    King, Moses
    King, W. W.
    Kingsley, Elbridge
    Kinney, Louise W.
    Kirby, Thomas E.
    Kirkpatrick, Frank L.
    Klackner, C.
    Klein, Jacob
    Knowlton, W. J.
    Koecker, L. R.
    Kramer, John
    Kress, Charles
  - K, Miscellaneous: Ku, 1882-1888 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    Kudlich, H. C.
    Kunz, George F.
    Kurtz, Charles M.
    Kurtz, W.
  - Laffan, William Mackay, 1874-1880 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Lange, Johs. D., 1868-1890, undated, (18 folders) (Box 3, Folder 61-78)
  - Lathrop, George P., 1879-1886 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Lee, John W. M., 1885-1889 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Lehrs, M., 1888-1890 (Box 3, Folder 81)